<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming category on RΞCURSION</title><link>https://carlvinjerry.github.io/posts/quantitative-finance/</link><description>Recent content in Programming category on RΞCURSION</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://carlvinjerry.github.io/posts/quantitative-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Stochastic Differential Equations</title><link>https://carlvinjerry.github.io/posts/quantitative-finance/intro-to-sdes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlvinjerry.github.io/posts/quantitative-finance/intro-to-sdes/</guid><description>This post introduces SDEs and the Euler-Maruyama method, demonstrating their application in finance and ESG modeling. Through F# simulations of stock prices and renewable energy adoption, we show how to implement and visualize SDE solutions, highlighting their importance for handling uncertainty.</description></item><item><title>Simple Moving Average Crossover Strategy in F#</title><link>https://carlvinjerry.github.io/posts/quantitative-finance/moving-averages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 21:37:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://carlvinjerry.github.io/posts/quantitative-finance/moving-averages/</guid><description>Basic Components If you&amp;rsquo;re new to algorithmic trading, a moving average crossover strategy is one of the simplest and most popular approaches. It works by comparing two averages of an asset&amp;rsquo;s price over different time periods to identify potential buy or sell signals.
How It Works Short-Term Average: Calculates the average price over recent days (e.g., 5 days)
Long-Term Average: Calculates the average price over a longer period (e.g., 20 days)</description></item><item><title>Attributing for Risk in Portfolio Management</title><link>https://carlvinjerry.github.io/posts/quantitative-finance/portfolio-risk-attribution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 21:37:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://carlvinjerry.github.io/posts/quantitative-finance/portfolio-risk-attribution/</guid><description>Risk contribution helps quantify how much each asset in a portfolio contributes to its overall risk. However, unlike with portfolio returns, a key aspect of portfolio risk is that its measures —like volatility— must adhere to certain statistical properties such as monotonicity, sub-additivity, homogeneity, and translation invariance. The non-linear nature of these formulae therefore makes it a chellenge to split apart and determine individual contributions of each asset to the overal portfolio risk.</description></item></channel></rss>